2017

MOHAMAD HAFIZ B. YAHAYA

ruang2kosong@yahoo.com



Mailing Address : 167,

Jalan Bukit Puteri 21/6, Bandar Puteri Jaya, 08000 Sungai Petani,

Kedah.

Contact No. (Mobile) : +6012 5098316

Professional Profile

I am an enthusiastic and professional person who have experiences as a Visual Artist, Creative Designer and Art Academician who enjoys being part of, as well as leading, a successful and productive team. I am quick to grasp new ideas and concepts, and to develop innovative and creative solutions to problems. I am able to work well on my own initiative and can demonstrate the high levels of motivation. As an academician and practicing visual artist, I have a good experience both in academic and practicing area especially in visual art and design.

Objective

I am now looking to build on my extensive range of technical and theoretical skills within a suitably challenging role. I am keen to achieve further professional development in academic and research field related to art & design area.

Personal Particulars

Age : 34 years old Race : Malay
Date of birth : 01 February 1983 Religion : Islam
Nationality : Malaysian Marital Status : Married

Language : English, Malay Health : Excellent; non-smoker

Formal Qualification

Post graduate education (2014 - 2015)

Field of Study : Masters in Art & Design (mix mode)
Institute / University : Universiti Sains Malaysia (USM)

Undergraduate education (2004 - 2006)

Field of Study : Bachelor with honors in Fine Art (BFA) GP.A 3.15

Major: SculptureMinor: Painting

Institute / University : Universiti Teknologi MARA (UiTM)

Undergraduate education (2001 - 2004)

Field of Study : Diploma in Art & Design (Fine Art) GP.A 2.99

Institute / University : Universiti Teknologi MARA (UiTM)

Qualification & Achievement

Others Achievement: Finalist, Upstart' 05: The Nokia Creative Art Awards (Visual Art) 2005

Finalist, Young and Contemporary (Visual Art) 2006 Finalist, Young and Contemporary (Visual Art) 2010

Key Technical Skills in visual art & design

Painting - oil, acrylic, mural

Sculpture - foam, wood, steel, clay, plaster, welding and forging

Digital Art - adobe photoshop, adobe illustrator, adobe premiere

Foundation Art - basic design, basic drawing

Art History & Art Theory - visual art & design

Research - visual art & design, social science

Writings and publications

Objek Harian, Memori dan Momen serta Hubungkaitnya dengan Karya Seni Visual - Published in IDEOLOGY II (Jurnal Seni dan Budaya Malaysia – Indonesia). Journal by Uitm Perak & ISBI Bandung, 2016

Hubungkait Diantara Pelukis dan Penjenamaan - Published in IDEOLOGY **(**Jurnal Seni dan Budaya Malaysia - Indonesia). Journal by Uitm Perak & ISBI Bandung, 2016

Kejayaan Pensyarah dan Pelajar FSSR UiTM Perak di dalam Pertandingan Bakat Muda Sezaman - Published in Canang a journal by UiTM Perak, 2015

Momen : Rekonstur Objek Lama Dalam Mentafsir Memori Peribadi- Published in TRANSMIT: Siri Esei & Kajian Praktis Studio Seni. Journal by USM, 2015

PERIPETEIA : Legasi Titik Pemula Buat Pelukis - Final year M.A (mix mode) student art exhibition catalogue, USM, 2015

WET Coal (Alternative Charcoal from Waste Material) – research paper in Asian Fiber Arts, UiTM Perak, 2011

Interests & Activities

Fine Art, Digital Arts, Video Arts and Technology, Foundation Art & Design, Art History, Sosiology and Academic Research.

Career Summary

Visual Artist

Job Responsibility : Participate in art exhibition and events from 2003 - present (see attached visual artist

CV)

Lecturer in Fine Art Department

Position : Part Time Full Time Lecture – Dis 2007 – March 2008

: Young Lecture (contract) - Apr 2008 - March 2012 : Part Time Full Time Lecture - June 2014 - Apr 2015

Job Responsibility : Lecturing Sculpture, subject such as form and mould and welding and forging (form).

: Lecturing Time Based Media, subject such as digital art (image manipulation, digital

painting and video).

: Lecturing Painting, subject such as pastel, acrylic, collage and oil painting.

: Lecturing basic design and drawing for foundation art class

: Lecturing art history and contemporary art development in Malaysia

Institution : Universiti Technology Mara (UiTM) Perak

Mural Painter (2006-2007) - free lance

Job Responsibility : Paint a mural.

Clients : Norwegian Star Cruise Ship at Singapore, Tadika Cahaya at Seksyen 27 Shah Alam and

various company in K.L.

Props Master (2006 - 2007) - free lance

Job Responsibility : Build up props and finishing.

Events : Sambutan 50 tahun Kemerdekaan, K.L (props) / Mega Sale at Khoo Kongsi, Penang

(props) / Pameran Sains dan Kesenian Islam at Planetarium Negara K.L (special

effect painter) and various events.

Interior Paintings (2006 - 2007) - free lance

Job Responsibility : Paint an interior paintings for decoration and display.

Clients : The Traders Hotel, K.L / 4Season House of Art & Design and various company in K.L.

Others Experiences

Public Art Project (team)

Arca MINDA at Dataran Dewan Seri Iskandar UiTM Perak, 2012

• Artist in Residence

Gudang Alternative Space at Damansara, 2007

• Art Facilitator/Judge

Exxon Mobile children drawing at Dataran Merdeka (organized by National Art Gallery, 2006

References

1. Name : Dr. Mohammad Khizal b. Mohamed Saat

Contact Address : Schools of Art (USM)

Contact No : 019 4754163

2. Name : Dr. Muhammad Abdul Aziz B. Ab.Ghani Contact Address : Faculty of Art & Design (UiTM, Perak)

Contact No : 013 5181311